欢迎收看《热舞之夜》
Welcome to Night of Dance,
美国最受欢迎的舞蹈比赛
American favorite dance competition.
有请主持人
With your host,
布莱德·梅维尔
Brad Melville.
晚上好  美国
Good evening, America.
又到了一决舞功的时间
It's dance-off time,
今晚主题是拉丁舞
and the theme is Latin.
一如既往  今夜的挑战者
As always, tonight's challengers
都是经过评委精心选拔出来的
were hand picked by the judges.
麦克斯  你期待看到两位挑战者跳伦巴舞吗
Max, are you looking forward to watching these two Rumba?
我期待桑蒂诺能挽回
I'm looking forward to Santino redeeming himself
上周桑巴风格独舞的失利
for his Samba-inspired solo dance last week.
惨不忍睹
Pathetic.
就像我的狗吃了巴西大餐的剩菜
It was like a terrible dream my dog would have
之后做的噩梦
after eating the leftovers of my Brazilian dinner.
大家都见过我们的半决赛选手了
You know our semifinalists.
对决阵容是  桑蒂诺对
Our matchup is-- Santino versus...
奥黛特
Odette.
傲慢的坏男孩能打败美国甜心吗
Can the arrogant bad boy best America's sweetheart?
让比赛马上开始吧
Let's get right to it.
今夜在桑蒂诺和奥黛特间进行的淘汰赛
Tonight's elimination dance between Santino and Odette
意味着他们中的一个将走到尽头
will mean the end of the road for one of them.
他们中一人将在周一结果揭晓节目中被淘汰
One will be eliminated on Monday's results show.
而另一个将晋级总决赛二强
The other will be guaranteed a spot in the final two.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen--
有请桑蒂诺和奥黛特
Santino and Odette!
奥黛特  在吗
Odette, are you in there?
猜猜我今天在美容院碰到谁了
Guess who I ran into at the beauty parlor today?
妈妈  我正写到关键地方而且
Mother, I'm at a critical juncture and--
乌娜·马可尼
Oona Marconi.
那个剧评家乌娜·马可尼吗
Oona Marconi the theater critic?
我想请她吃饭
I thought I might invite her to dinner.
请她在她的专栏里
Ask her to give a little mention to my acting school,
提一提我的表演学校
put it into one of her columns.
这会是非常有效的宣传
It would be invaluable publicity.
是的  但那得看怎么提
Yes, well, that would depend on the mention.
你没忘记她对你在《热铁皮屋顶上的猫》中
You aren't forgetting her blistering review...of your performance
饰演的玛吉的刻薄评论吧
of Maggie in "Cat on a hot tin roof", are you?
那是1983年
That was 1983.
事情已经过去了
I think I'm over it.
"玛莎·罗杰斯饰演的"小猫"玛吉
"Martha Rodgers as Maggie the cat
更像一只无助的猫咪
is more of a helpless kitten,
只要不能如愿就又是拍手又是喵喵叫"
mewing and flapping her hands when she doesn't get her way."
你记下来了
You memorized it?
没办法
I couldn't help it.
几个月里你都在公寓里走来走去念叨着这句话
You walked around the apartment quoting it for months.
妈妈  我想说的是
Mother, I'm just saying,
也许找一个曾对你不怎么友善的人
maybe it's not a good idea to ask
帮你这么重要的忙
an important favor of someone who's been
不是个好主意
so... unkind to you in the past.
这里的关键词是"曾"
The operative word here is "Past."
我想我可以不受这事的影响
I think I can rise above.
另外  我的表演学校
Besides, my acting school
对我来说比那些陈年旧事重要多了
is more important to me than some old grudge.
这可真成熟  妈妈
Well, that's very mature of you, mother.
谢谢
Thank you.
"如果田纳西·威廉斯知道玛莎·罗杰斯
"If Tennessee Williams knew what crimes Martha Rodgers
以他的名义对观众犯下的罪行
had committed against this audience in his name,
他会以伤害罪逮捕她"
he would have her arrested for assault."
不受影响
Rising above.
别逗了  卡塞尔  这个剧作家能有多刻薄
Come on, Castle. How mean can this critic be?
我只是怕她是在自寻伤心
I'm just afraid that she's gonna get her heart broken, you know?
你知道我妈妈
I mean, you know my mother.
看外表  坚强自信
On the exterior, she's a tough cookie.
她的虚张声势其实掩藏了
But underneath all that bravado--
她脆弱的心
gooey center.
蕾妮
Hey, Lanie.
死者是谁
So who's our victim?
奥黛特·莫顿
Odette Morton.
死因是心脏中一枪
'cause of death is a single G.S.W. to the heart.
可能是9毫米的子弹  她当场死亡
Probably a 9 millimeter. She died instantly.
子弹穿透了她的身体
The bullet went right through her.
除非凶手用了消音器
Well, unless our killer used a silencer
否则肯定有人听到枪声
someone must have heard the shot.
不一定
Not necessarily.
根据舞台经理说的  开始录制节目时
According to the stage manager, this area clears out
这里就没人了
once taping starts.
另外开幕焰火也会掩盖枪声
Plus the opening pyrotechnics could've covered a gunshot.
那前提是她正好是在节目开场时中枪的
Well, that's assuming that she was shot just as the show started.
看起来就是这样
It looks like she was.
是的
Yeah, the, uh,
化妆师在三点差一刻给奥黛特画完妆
makeup girl finished with Odette at 2:45,
三点开始录制节目
Taping starts at 3:00,
三点过四分发现她的尸体
and she was discovered at 3:04.
十九分钟  很短的时间区
19 minutes. That's not a very big window.
去问问有没有员工看见有谁靠近这间房间
All right, see if the crew saw anyone near this room around that time.
没问题
You got it.
莱恩  能给我份今晚被邀请来
Hey, Ryan. Can I get a list of all the guests
参与录制的所有来宾
that were invited to tonight's taping
和在保安那里登过记的人员名单吗
along with anyone that checked in at security?
已经在统计了
Uh, already on it,
但那不是唯一的入口
but that's not the only way in here.
大厅的走廊尽头还有一个安全出口
There's an exit door to the alley down the hall.
工作人员经常把门开着
The crew guys like to prop it open
好出去抽根烟
so they can go out for a smoke.
那么要么凶手碰巧找到了没锁的们
So either our killer got lucky and found an unlocked door...
要么是内部人员作案
Or this was an inside job.
我也认为是这样
That gets my vote.
奥黛特肯定会胜出
Odette was a lock to win this thing.
我打赌是她哪个卑鄙的对手干的
I bet it was one of her backstabbing rivals that did this.
怎么啦  我看这个节目
What? I watch the show.
奥黛特是我最喜欢的选手
Odette was my favorite contestant.
她是有钱祖父养大的女继承人
She was an heiress raised by her rich grandpa,
一个误入歧途的派对女郎
a party girl headed down the wrong path,
与死亡擦肩而过令她幡然醒悟
then a brush with death made her wake up
改变了她的坏女孩作风
and change her bad-girl ways.
故事不错
That's a great story.
就是结局不如人意
Except for the ending.
我得说  帕里什医生
I gotta say, Dr. Parish.
没想到你会是《热舞之夜》的粉丝
I never figured you for a fan of "A night of dance".
其实我不是
I'm not exactly.
只是
It's just...
我小时候  最大的梦想就是
When I was young, more than anything,
成为首席芭蕾舞演员
I wanted to be a prima ballerina.
我没跳舞的时候心里也想着跳舞
If I wasn't dancing, I was thinking about dancing.
那么发生了什么事
So what happened?
我十三岁的时候开始发育
The girls came along when I was 13.
跳芭蕾的没几个是波涛汹涌的
Not that many top-heavy ballerinas out there.
我觉得该多点这样的
Well, I think there should be.
你当然喜闻乐见了
Of course you do.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
不过呢...
Although...
奥黛特有什么亲属吗
Does Odette have any next of kin?
保罗·莫顿  她的哥哥
Um, Paul Morton, her brother.
好  把他带过来
Okay, great. Bring him down here.
和剩下的选手聊聊
And talk to the rest of the contestants,
我想知道是不是有人
I want to see if anyone is taking this competition
把这场比赛看的太认真了
just a little too seriously.
我们了解到你和奥黛特
We understand that you and Odette
一整天都在排练你们的舞蹈
were rehearsing your dance most of the day.
她看起来怎么样
How did she seem?
她很紧张  我们两个都是
On edge. We both were.
我们之中会有一个人被淘汰
I mean, one of us was about to be eliminated,
所以我不敢相信她彩排到11点就走了
which is why I can't believe she just left rehearsal at 11:00
竟然离开了半个小时
and took off for half an hour.
-去做什么了  -她不说
- To do what? - She wouldn't say.
但是这支舞将决定一切
But everything was riding on this dance.
她告诉我她要去见一个朋友
She told me she had to meet a friend.
如果有人找她让我掩护一下
She asked me to cover if anyone was looking for her.
你知道她
Um... do you have any idea
为什么遮遮掩掩的吗
why she was being so secretive?
制作人不喜欢我们在演出当天离开演播室
The producers don't like us to leave the studio on show day.
所以一定是重要的事
So it must have been important.
纽约警察局
Well, the NYPD thanks you
感谢你的配合
for your cooperation.
也感谢你
You, too.
靠
Damn.
-你看见了吗  -嗯
- Did you see that? - Mm-hmm.
她好像装作我不存在一样
She acted like I didn't even exist.
你确实不存在
You don't.
你带上戒指的那一刻起你就不存在了
Not since you put that ring on your finger.
习惯单身女性把你当隐形人的现实吧
Get used to being invisible to single women.
我从来没有见她像过去几个月这么开心过
I've never seen her happier than these past couple months.
我真不敢想象我的妹妹死了
I can't believe that my sister's dead.
我们知道她
We understand she had some...
过去有一些困难
difficulties in the past.
几年前  我们的祖父去世了
A few years ago, our grandfather passed away,
奥黛特很难接受这个事实
and Odette took it hard.
她退了学
Uh, she quit school,
和一个很好的人分了手
she broke off her relationship with a nice guy,
开始和不正经的人鬼混
started hanging out with a bad crowd.
什么样的不正经人呢
What kind of bad crowd?
派对动物和吸毒的
You know, partiers and druggies.
她被逮捕了很多次
She was arrested several times.
但是事故过后  她就改过自新了
But after the accident, she left all of that behind.
你是指她差点死掉那次
That was her brush with death?
是去年的一次火车脱轨事件
It was a train derailment last year.
奥黛特在车上
Odette was on board.
她成功得活下来了  但把她吓得不轻
She made it out alive, but it scared the hell out of her.
于是她改变了自己的人生轨迹
She turned her life around.
六个月的舞蹈训练  接下来我知道的就是
Six months of dance training, and the next thing that I know,
她试镜了《热舞之夜》
she's auditioned for "A night of dance"
而且被选中了
and been accepted.
她终于找到了人生中的方向
She finally found a direction in life.
她差一点就圆了自己的梦
She was so close to realizing her dream.
奥黛特生前有没有
Was there anyone in Odette's old life
可能给她带来麻烦的人
that could've come back to cause trouble for her?
据我所知没有
Not that I'm aware of.
演出中呢  有没有和她不合的人
What about on the show? Anyone she didn't get along with?
呃  她确实提到了一个人
Uh, uh, she did mention someone,
另外一个选手
another contestant.
我记着她说他的名字是艾迪
I think she said his name was Eddie.
贝克特探长  他们在里边等你呢
Detective Beckett, they're waiting for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett,
做为《热舞之夜》的合作创始人和制作人
as co-creator and executive producer of "Night of Dance"
我已经吩咐我的员工
I have instructed my staff to provide you
为你提供任何你需要
with anything and everything you need
来破这起谋杀案的帮助
to help solve this terrible murder.
-任何事  -绝对的
- Anything. - Absolutely anything.
非常感谢
Thanks.
奥黛特告诉她的哥哥剧组里
Now Odette told her brother that there was someone
有个人和她合不来
on the show that she didn't get along with.
艾迪·戈登  但是他已经不在了
Eddie Gordon, but he's not here anymore.
上周  艾迪和奥黛特在淘汰赛中
Last week, Eddie and Odette performed
表演了一段受鲍勃·弗希启发的一段舞蹈
a Bob-Fosse-inspired number for the elimination dance-off.
我们投票把艾迪淘汰了
We voted and sent Eddie home.
他很沮丧
He was upset.
-有多沮丧  -你得知道
- How upset? - Well, you have to understand,
所有的参赛者都会在节目中
all the contestants are cast on this show
讲述他们独特但又熟悉的故事
to tell their unique yet familiar stories.
奥黛特是个可怜的富家女孩
Odette was the poor little rich girl,
而艾迪却是个贫穷的痞子
and Eddie was the kid from the wrong side of the tracks.
我们选艾迪是为了戏剧效果
We cast Eddie to bring the drama.
艾迪带来了戏剧效果
Eddie brought the drama
而他带来的戏剧效果不光光是镜头前的
and not just for the cameras.
我们让他打包走人的时候他很生气
He was furious when we sent him packing.
话讲的相当难听
and we all got an earful about it.
他太无礼了
Oh, and he was so rude.
我不得不叫保安
I had to call security.
他有威胁任何人吗
Was he threatening?
这么说吧  他走了之后我松了一口气
Let's just say, I was relieved when he was gone.
不过真是很讽刺
Ironic, really.
为什么
How so?
根据赛制
Well, according to the rules,
当一个参赛者不能继续参赛
when a contestant is unable to continue,
上一个被淘汰的舞者会回来
the last eliminated dancer returns
代替他或她的位置
to take his or her place.
而那个人就是艾迪·戈登
And that dancer is Eddie Gordon.
让我告诉你一些
Let me tell you something
关于单纯可爱小姐奥黛特的事吧
about Miss sweet-and-innocent Odette.
她今天晚上阴我
She threw me under the bus tonight.
她缺席了整整一周的彩排
She blew off rehearsals all week,
她搞错了自己的舞步  还把失误怪在我身上
then messed up her footwork and blames it on me.
知道按我们那儿的规矩
Where I'm from, we know what to do
怎么对付这样撒谎的婊子吗
with lying bitches like that.
那是艾迪的临别采访
That was Eddie's exit interview.
制片人鼓励选手们放开了说
The contestants are encouraged by producers to speak freely.
他显然是采纳了他们的意见
He certainly took their advice.
艾迪在罗切斯特有犯罪记录
Eddie has got a record back home in Rochester,
一位《热舞之夜》的助理说
and one of the assistants at "A night of dance"
记得在奥黛特被杀的那天下午
says they remember seeing him in the studio
在摄影棚看到了他
the afternoon Odette was murdered.
那么艾迪被淘汰了
Okay, so Eddie was eliminated,
但是他知道如果奥黛特不能参加比赛
but he knew that if Odette was out of the running,
他就会被叫回来代替她的位置
he'd be asked to return and take her slot.
所以他回来"淘汰"奥黛特
So he went back and eliminated Odette...
永久地淘汰
Permanently.
入室抢劫  盗窃
B&E, robbery--
你在罗切斯特还真是忙啊  艾迪
you were pretty busy up in Rochester, Eddie.
没错  但那是很久前的事了
Yeah, but that was a long time ago.
开始跳舞之后我就不过恶棍一样的生活了
When I started dancing, I gave up thug life.
但当你被淘汰的时候
Yeah, well, that didn't stop you from going off
你还是对评委态度很恶劣
on the judges when you were eliminated.
淘汰我是他们错误的选择
Me going home was the wrong call
我就是这么说的
and I said so.
或许我说出来了
Maybe I said it loud,
但说狠话可不代表我是杀人凶手
but that don't make me no killer.
现在奥黛特不能完成比赛
Now that Odette can't finish the competition,
上一个被淘汰的选手会被叫回来参赛
the last eliminated contestant will be asked to return,
那个人就是你  艾迪
and that's you, Eddie.
就像我爸爸曾经说的
Like my daddy used to say,
天道难测
the universe works in mysterious ways.
也许你决定"助天行道"
And maybe you decided to give the universe just a little shove.
录制那天你在演播室做什么
So what were you doing at the studio on show day?
我提前过来看我兄弟桑蒂诺
I went by early to see my boy Santino.
为他的大日子鼓鼓劲
Give him support on his big day.
你还真是对答如流  艾迪
You got an answer for everything, don't you, Eddie?
知道你还有什么吗
And you know what else you got?
你有动机和动手的机会
You got motive and opportunity.
这事发生时我正在城市的另一头
Man, I was across town when that mess happened,
见我的经纪人
meeting my agent.
但上周  奥黛特确实有些事缠身
But last week, something was going on with Odette...
一些和跳舞无关的事
Something that didn't have nothing to do with dancing.
-什么意思  -她练舞时不在状态
- What do you mean? - She was out of it.
跳错简单的舞步
Missing easy steps,
她说要去洗手间
she'd say she's going to the ladies room,
却一去半小时
and then be gone for half an hour.
你觉得她在干什么
What do you think she was doing?
我知道她在干什么
I know what she was doing.
我看见她从后门穿出
I saw her go out the back door,
在小巷里和个男人见面
meet some guy in the alley.
他们很严肃地谈了一会儿
They talked real serious for a minute,
然后她给了他一卷钞票
then she handed him a roll of bills.
好像有三千
Looked like 3 grand easy.
你有看清楚那个男人吗
You get a good enough look at this guy?
能为我们画幅肖像吗
You think you can provide us with a sketch?
可以  我能办到
Yeah. I can do that.
艾迪·戈登说的是真话
So Eddie Gordon spoke the truth.
奥黛特别杀时  他确实正见经纪人
He was meeting with his agent when Odette was shot.
那他说看见奥黛特在小巷里
So maybe he was also telling the truth
和个男人见面也可能是真话了
about the guy he saw Odette with in the alley.
他为我们画了幅肖像
Well, he gave us a sketch.
但是没啥特点
Pretty generic, though.
深发白人帅哥
Handsome, caucasian, dark hair.
可能她在中枪那天
You know, that missing half-hour when Odette left rehearsal
离开排练的半小时
the day she was shot--
就是和他在一起
maybe she was with him.
我会让警员在演播室周围散播肖像
I'll have uniforms circulate the sketch around the studio,
看是否有人能认出他
see if anybody recognizes him.
如果奥黛特在列车事故后回归正道
Okay, so if Odette had straightened up after the train accident,
那她在后台门外偷偷
What was she doing behind the stage door
给人一卷钱是为什么
secretly giving some guy a roll of bills?
可能是毒品交易
Could be a drug deal.
也许奥黛特的又犯老毛病了
Maybe Odette was falling back into old habits.
银行账单上有近期的提款记录吗
Any recent withdrawals in her bank statement?
没有那么大的数额  可看看...
Yeah, not for that amount of money, but check out...
这些信用卡支付记录
these credit card payments.
在过去的半年里  奥黛特的信用卡支出
For the last six months, Odette's credit card spending
都很稳定  但大约一个月前
was pretty much steady, and then about a month ago,
它却猛然增加了
it suddenly shot up.
可不是  她卡都刷爆了
No kidding. Her cards were maxed out.
花费超过十万美元了
Over 100 grand in charges?
她把这些钱都花哪了
What was she spending all that money on?
谢谢你的到来  林奇伯格先生
Thank you for coming in, Mr. Lynchberg.
你既是奥黛特的业务经理
You were Odette's business manager
也是她祖父财产的遗嘱执行人吗
as well as the executor of her grandfather's estate?
很不幸  现在还需
And now I have the unfortunate task
处理奥黛特的财产
of handling Odette's estate as well.
那谁会继承她在家族信托中的份额
And who inherits her share of the family trust?
遵照奥黛特的遗嘱
Per Odette's wishes,
份额会归格兰姆·莫顿基金会
it goes to the Graham Morton Foundation.
这是个慈善组织
It's a charitable organization.
我留意到上月她的开销
You know, I noticed a pretty big spike
有了非常大的增幅
in her spending over the last month.
-你知道是怎么回事吗  -相信你知道
- Do you have any idea what that was about? - I'm sure you know
自从三年前奥黛特的祖父过世后
that after Odette's grandfather passed away three years ago,
她经历了一段黑暗时期
she went through a bad period.
是的  她哥哥已告知我们了
Yeah, her brother filled us in--
开派对  吸毒
parties, drugs.
那时候我尤其关心的就是她的开销
Of particular concern to me during that time was her spending.
她会喝得烂醉  突然就买辆车
Odette would get drunk and spontaneously buy a car
或是投标一间新公寓
or put a bid down on a new apartment.
她还会为朋友的隆鼻手术买单
She paid for her friend's nose job--
就是随心所欲  肆意妄为
just whatever struck her fancy.
但在去年列车事故之后
But then after the train accident last year,
一切都停止了
all that stopped.
这使关心她的我们都舒了一口气
It was, uh, refreshing to those of us who cared about her.
我当时担心她上月的挥金如土是
I was worried that last month's credit card charges
故态复萌的表现
indicated that she might have been backsliding.
她都买了什么
What was she buying?
大部分都是衣服
Clothing mostly.
那两天大部分开销
The bulk of the charges were over two days
都在第五大道的一家百货公司
at one particular 5th Avenue Department Store.
我想看看原始收据
I'd like to see the original receipts.
当然可以
Of course.
这是我见过最奇怪的大血拼了
This is the weirdest spending spree I have ever seen.
奥黛特在衣服上花了上万的美元
Odette spent tens of thousands of dollars on clothes,
但从收据来看  衣服都不是她的尺码
but nothing in her size according to these receipts.
所有的衣服都是4号
Everything's in size 4.
而我搜查过她的公寓
And I went through her apartment.
也没看见价值十万的新衣服
I didn't see 100 grand worth of new clothes.
也许她把它们藏起来了
Maybe she hid 'em.
我听着像经典的加油卡诡计
Sounds to me like the old gas card scam.
什么意思
What do you mean?
父母对你的零用钱管得非常严
Your parents put you on a strict allowance,
但他们给你张加油卡  好让你替车加油
but they give you a gas card so you can fill your car.
你替朋友的车加油
Well, you fill your friends cars,
然后他们就给你现金
and they give you cash.
我一些在寄宿学校的朋友
Some of my buddies in boarding school
-就这样使零用钱翻了倍  -是嘛
- nearly doubled their allowance. - Uh-huh.
当然不是我
Not me, of course.
那...
That...
可别告诉我妈
Don't tell my mother.
这么说  如果奥黛特急着要现金
So if Odette needed cash in a hurry to,
比如要在小巷里付钱给谁...
say, maybe pay off some guy in an alley...
可每月家族信托所给的津贴
But the monthly stipend from her family trust
并不足以支付
wasn't enough to cover it.
所以她买衣服  再倒卖给朋友
So she charges the clothes, sells them to her friends,
周转点现金
in some cash flow.
但这些仍不够
Which is still not enough.
但信用卡刷爆  没法换钱了
The card's maxed out, the money train stops,
她不能付款给债主了
and she can't make payment to whoever she owes.
所以她死了
She ends up dead.
可你们真认为奥黛特有个
Yeah, but do you guys think that Odette actually had
穿4码衣服的朋友
one size 4 friend
愿意花十万美元买一堆小脚牛仔裤和
willing to pay 100 grand for a bunch of pegged jeans
一个人造兔毛手提包吗
and a faux rabbit purse?
你刚才说兔毛吗
Did you say rabbit?
贾思敏
Jasmine.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
你是从哪里得到这包的
Where'd you get the bag?
一个朋友给我的
A friend gave it to me.
是你的朋友奥黛特·莫顿吗
Your friend Odette Morton?
我们和售货员谈过了  贾思敏
We talked to the salesperson, Jasmine.
她说奥黛特当时跟你在一起
She said that you were with Odette
给你买了十万块的衣服
when she dropped 100 grand on clothes for you.
奥黛特是个非常慷慨的人
Odette was very generous.
但她死了
She's also very dead,
我一听就知道这是个勒索骗局
and I know a blackmail scheme when I hear one.
也许奥黛特确实遇到了一些
Maybe Odette had something going on in her life
不想让别人知道的事
she wanted to keep secret.
可是被你发现了
You found out about it and told her
想要封住你的口  就得跟你买一整柜衣服
that the price for your silence was a closet full of fancy duds.
那我为何杀她呢
But why would I kill her?
也许她不能继续满足你了  你很失望
Maybe she couldn't give anymore, you got frustrated,
然后就杀了她
you killed her.
又或者她决定公开秘密
Maybe she decided to come forward herself,
告你勒索
accuse you of blackmail,
然后你杀了她
you killed her.
贾思敏  我能想到的情节多了去了
Jasmine, these are just off the top of my head.
-我们回警局再说吧  -等等
- We can finish off this conversation at the precinct. - Wait.
上个月  我有天很晚下班
Last month, I was here working late,
正好撞见奥黛特匆忙从我的位置旁经过
and I happened to see Odette walk by my desk real fast,
一脸苦闷  然后我看到
like she was upset. Next thing I know,
布莱德·梅维尔出现了  好像是来找她
here comes Brad Melville, like he's looking for her.
布莱德·梅维尔  节目的主持吗
Brad Melville, the show's host?
《热舞之夜》的主持人来找
Why would the host of "A Night of Dance"
一个参赛选手干嘛
be looking for a contestant?
主持和选手不是禁止有交情吗
Aren't they not supposed to fraternize?
所以我跟了上去
That's why I followed him.
布莱德和奥黛特在楼梯间吵了一架
Brad and Odette were in the stairwell having a fight.
吵了些什么
About what?
我不是很清楚
I'm not completely sure.
不过我吓唬奥黛特
But when I bluffed Odette
要把她跟布莱德的事告诉麦克斯时
that I was going to tell Max about her and Brad,
她特别紧张
she got really nervous.
她说她可以给我点好处  让我别说出去
She offered to buy me some stuff I wanted if I'd keep quiet.
我觉得这交易不错
And I thought that sounded like a good deal.
但事情到此为止  我绝不会伤害奥黛特的
But that's it. I would've never hurt Odette.
不好意思  你这话实在让人难以相信
You'll have to pardon me if I don't take you at your word.
如果说有谁想杀奥黛特
Look, if anyone had a reason to murder Odette,
肯定就是布莱德
it was Brad.
我有录音为证
Just listen. I recorded the two of them.
我们明明说好了的
We had a deal.
如果你不说出去  我也不说
And I'm willing to stand by it if you are.
我辛辛苦苦才爬到现在这个位置
I have worked too hard to get where I am.
如果别人知道这事  奥黛特
If anyone finds out about this, Odette,
你就死定了
I swear, I'll kill you.
麦克斯·兰弗罗要是发现布莱德·梅维尔
If Max Renfro found out that Brad Melville
跟某个选手有来往
was in a relationship with one of the contestants,
他会怎么做
what would happen?
选手会被开除
She'd be thrown off the show,
主持人也是
and he'd be fired.
足够作为谋杀动机了  谁有异议不
Motive for murder, anyone?
如果有别人知道这事  奥黛特
If anyone finds out about this, Odette,
你就死定了
I swear, I'll kill you.
事情不是你们听到的那样
That is completely not what it sounds like.
布莱德  我们听到的是  在奥黛特
What it sounds like, Brad, is you threatening
死前数周  你威胁过奥黛特·莫顿
Odette Morton's life a few weeks before she was murdered.
可我当初是想要保护她
But I was trying to protect her.
怎么个保护法
Protect her how?
我知道奥黛特有过一段麻烦史
I knew about Odette's troubled past--
总是嗑药  酒后驾车
the drugs, the D.U.I.s.
可她说现在都戒了  还说跳舞
But I also believed her when she said she was clean now
是她最在乎的事情  我也信过她
and that dancing was all she cared about.
你是想说她在撒谎吗
Are you trying to say that that wasn't true?
我想说的是
What I'm trying to say is,
两个月前  我有一天很早就去化妆
two months ago, I walked into makeup early one morning,
结果发现奥黛特在注射毒品
and found Odette shooting up.
你确定吗
Are you sure about this?
百分之百确定
100% positive.
要是让麦克斯知道这事
If Max knew she was using,
她肯定会被当场淘汰
she would've been eliminated on the spot.
可你没告诉麦克斯
But you never told max.
奥黛特发誓她会戒掉
Odette promised she would clean up.
我就给了她一次机会  但我一直有留意她
I gave her a second chance, but I also kept an eye on her.
然后一个月前  她又被我抓了现行
Then a month ago, I caught her again.
我跟她说我没法再帮她了  我得告诉麦克斯
I told her I was going to max, that she was on her own.
麦克斯知道了吗
And did you?
没有  因为奥黛特威胁我
No, because Odette threatened me.
她说如果我去麦克斯那里告密
She said that if I went to max and told him what I'd seen,
她就要告诉麦克斯
that she'd go to him and tell him that I was the one
我第一次放过了她
that let her off the first time.
麦克斯肯定会因为
Max would've fired me
我隐瞒了这么大秘密而开除我的
for keeping a secret that big from him.
我就做不了节目了
I'd be off the show.
我就成了布莱恩·邓克曼
I'd be Brian Dunkleman.
2002年第一季美国偶像的主持之一  季终后辞职
因后来节目大红  评论称其毁掉了自己的职业生涯
布莱恩·邓克曼是谁
Who's Brian Dunkleman?
看吧  没人知道他
Exactly.
就是说如果奥黛特被开除  她就要拉你当垫背
So... if Odette went down, she was taking you with her.
布莱德说的没错
Brad was right about her shooting up.
在她的珠宝箱的活底层里
Found these hidden in a false bottom
找到了这玩意儿  怪不得鉴证组
underneath her jewelry box. No wonder C.S.U. missed it.
-搜她公寓的时候没找到  -有可能是兴奋剂
- when they went through her apartment. - Could be speed.
可我刚跟蕾妮通过电话
Yeah, except I just got off the phone with Lanie,
她说毒理检验报告显示
and she said that preliminary tox screen results show
奥黛特没有吸毒
that Odette wasn't using drugs,
至少不是常见的毒品
at least none of the usual ones.
这针管里头到底是什么东西
So what the hell is in this bottle?
然后我跟劳伦斯爵士说  "拉瑞  这是
And so I said to Sir Laurence, "Larry, that is
这是我见过演《奥赛罗》的第二棒的演出
the second best performance of 'Othello' I have ever seen.
但是没有人能够超越
But I'm afraid no one can improve
奥森·威尔斯的表演"
the Orson Welles interpretation."
"拉瑞"  我对他说
"Larry," I said,
"你就是没他演得好"
"You've simply been outdone."
呃  那奥利弗怎么回答的
Wow. What did, uh, Olivier say to that?
他说...
He said...
"亲爱的
"My dear girl,
你还真有戏剧评论家的天赋"
you have the makings of a theater critic."
于是我就成了评论家
And so here I am.
是啊  你确实有天赋
Yes, indeed, you are.
噢对了
Oh, by the way,
不知道你最近听说没
I don't know if I told you that recently,
我开了一家表演学校
I opened my own acting school.
玛莎
Martha.
太棒了
How wonderful.
谢谢
Thank you.
你能把你
How good of you to share
"多年"的表演经验
your years and... years of experience
跟下一代分享真是太好了
with a new generation.
是啊  我们都为她感到自豪
Yes, we are very proud.
我在想
And I was wondering,
或许你可以赏脸来我的学校
perhaps you might consider stopping by
旁听一两堂课
and sitting in on a class or two,
如果觉得还不错的话
and then if you felt so inclined,
在你那个出色的专栏里
mentioning our little school
提几句我学校的事
in one of your wonderful columns.
我乐意之至
I'd be happy to do that.
你把时间地点告诉我就好
You just tell me where and when.
那太好了
Well, that's lovely.
希望你别把你那个在说重要台词前
I just hope you're not teaching your students
把头往一边倾斜的
your little trick of tilting your head
小动作教给学生们
before delivering an important line of dialogue.
我哪有这个动作
I don't do that.
你演"小猫"玛吉的时候就是这样的
Well, you did it when you played Maggie the cat.
对了  你双手还会像小鸟振翅那样抖动
Oh, and you fluttered your hands like little bird wings.
我一直等着你飞起来呢
I kept waiting for you to take off.
谁要吃派吗
Who wants pie?
阿丽克西斯  你能不能
Alexis, would you--
谢谢
Thank you.
我记得那年我获得了托尼奖的提名
I believe that was the year that I was nominated for a Tony.
也许比起我  美国戏剧协会
Well, perhaps the American Theatre Wing
对于歪头和乱挥手更宽容一些
is more tolerant of head tilting and hand fluttering than I am.
玛莎  我只是在开玩笑
Oh, Martha, I'm just teasing.
你不会还在为以前的那则评论生气吧
You can't possibly still be upset about that old review.
咱们别说会觉得后悔的话
Let's not say anything we'll regret.
那就不叫评论  那是诽谤
That was no review. That was a hatchet job.
根本就是毫无理由的恶意诽谤
It was vicious and it was uncalled for.
不过那的确是大实话
And it was also accurate.
别受影响
Rise above.
知道吗  乌娜  我撤回我的邀请
You know what, Oona? I rescind my request.
我现在绝不会接受你对我学校的赞扬
There is no way I would accept your endorsement of my school now
哪怕你求我
if you begged me.
没可能
Fat chance of that.
你记住  玛莎
Just remember, Martha,
演不利者  从教
those who can't do teach.
教不利者
And those who can't teach
评
become theater critics.
奶奶
Gram.
本可能更糟的
Could've been worse.
糟到极致了
It couldn't have been worse.
我妈妈敞开心扉
My mother exposed her gooey center,
乌娜·马可尼却扎了把刀子上去
and Oona Marconi drove a stake through it.
帮我转告她  我深表同情
Well, tell her, I feel her pain.
谢了  我会的  案子有什么进展吗
Thanks. I will. Anything new on the case?
警员找到了奥黛特遇害当天上午11点
Yeah, unis found the cafe that Odette went to at 11:00 a.m.
她去过的咖啡馆
the day that she was killed.
是去和神秘男子交易毒品吗
Scoring drugs off her mystery man?
是去喝杯脱脂拿铁
More like scoring a fat-free latte.
她约了个朋友喝咖啡
She met up with a friend for coffee.
苏珊·斯坦纳
Suzanne Steiner.
朋友
A friend?
录制日擅自离开可是件大事
Leaving the studio on show day was a very big deal.
有什么重要的事这么刻不容缓
What was so important that it couldn't wait?
苏珊说  她只是想叙叙旧
According to Suzanne, she just wanted to talk about old times.
实验室发来份传真
Hey, we got a fax from the lab.
我们在奥黛特公寓找到的小瓶清澈液体
That clear vial of liquid that we found at Odette's apartment?
不是违禁药品
It wasn't illegal drugs.
是胰岛素
It's insulin.
奥黛特有糖尿病吗
Odette was diabetic?
她医生说没有
Not according to her doctor.
他说已经一年多没见过她了
He said he hasn't seen her in over a year.
也许她是最近患上的
Well, maybe she developed it recently
有或者她换了个医生
or maybe she went to a new doctor.
那为什么不直接告诉布莱德·梅维尔实情呢
Then why not just tell Brad Melville the truth,
那并不是甲基苯丙胺[一种兴奋剂]只是胰岛素
that it wasn't speed, it was insulin?
何必要贿赂贾思敏呢
And why bother buying Jasmine half of 5th Avenue to keep it quiet?
我想我知道答案
Well, I think I can help with that.
奥黛特家的鉴证报告出来了
C.S.U. report is back on Odette's place.
他们只发现了一组指纹
They only found one set of prints
却不属于奥黛特
and they were not Odette's.
是一个叫芭芭拉·兰戴尔的女人的
They belong to a woman named Barbra Landau.
芭芭拉·兰戴尔又是谁
Who the hell is Barbra Landau?
是个不该跟奥黛特有交集的人
Not someone who would run in Odette's circles.
她在寄养家庭长大
She was raised in foster care
高中辍学
and was a high school dropout.
那她是和奥黛特一起住吗
So she was staying with Odette?
我们得和她谈谈
We need to talk to her.
八成是没戏了
That's gonna be tough.
据官方记录  芭芭拉·兰戴尔已经去世一年多了
Officially, Barbra Landau has been dead for over a year.
这是她的死亡证明
Here's her death certificate.
她在一场火车相撞事故中
She died of blunt force trauma
被钝器砸中致死
from injuries suffered in a train collision.
是的
That's right.
正是奥黛特幸存的那次火车事故
The same train collision that Odette survived.
可她真的幸存了吗
Or did she?
看到奥黛特的照片了吗
You see that picture of Odette?
这张是...
Well, this...
芭芭拉
is Barbra.
一模一样
They're identical.
不可能
But that's impossible.
不可能吗
Impossible
这或许是所有问题的答案
or the explanation to everything?
事故以后奥黛特发生了巨大的改变
The dramatic change in Odette after the accident,
还隐藏自己的糖尿病史
the need to hide being a diabetic,
因为奥黛特没有糖尿病
because Odette was not a diabetic...
奥黛特·莫顿并没在事故中幸存
Odette Morton didn't survive that train crash.
活下来的是芭芭拉
Barbra did.
如凤凰从灰烬中涅槃
And like a phoenix rising from the ashes,
芭芭拉·兰戴尔从火车残骸里爬出来
Barbra Landau walked away from the wreckage of that train
继而偷走了奥黛特·莫顿的生活
and stole Odette Morton's life.
双胞胎姐妹出生后被领养
Twin girls are born and put up for adoption.
奥黛特被有钱人家收养了
Odette goes to a wealthy, loving family.
芭芭拉就没那么幸运了
Barbra--not so lucky.
她辗转于寄养家庭之间
She gets bounced around from one foster home to the next,
可内心深处她一直知道
always knowing deep inside
她注定能过上更好的生活
that she was meant for something better.
然后有一天  她们在开往迈阿密的火车上相遇
Then one day, the two of them meet on a train bound for Miami.
姐妹之情一触即发
The connection is instantaneous.
在接下来的两天里  她们了解了彼此的一切
In two days, they learn everything there is to know about each other,
芭芭拉忍不住地想
And Barbra can't help but think,
假如当初我也像奥黛特那样进入富人家
If only I had landed in the lap of luxury like Odette,
我想干什么都行了
I could've been anything I wanted to be.
你是说芭芭拉为了夺走奥黛特的生活
Are you suggesting that Barbra purposefully caused the derailment
制造了脱轨事故吗
to take over Odette's life?
怎么办到的  用巫术吗
With what, her crazy wiccan powers?
那就会是个惊人大逆转了
Wow, that would be an incredible twist,
不是  当然不是
But no, no.
事故就是事故
The accident happens.
奥黛特遇害
Odette is killed.
芭芭拉幸存
Barbra survives.
混乱之中
And in the midst of all the chaos and rubble,
她看到了机会
she sees her chance.
她跟奥黛特换了身份
She switches identification with Odette,
改变了自己的命运
and she changes her destiny.
仅用一步  芭芭拉就为自己
In one move, Barbra builds herself
建立了一个更美好的未来和完美人生
a better future, a perfect life.
直到一年后还是被害了
Until she was murdered a year later.
"失散多年的双胞胎"这种故事
Yeah, well, separated twin stories
从来不会有好结局
never end happily,
除了《天生一对》
except "The Parent Trap."
血液报告来了
Blood tests are back.
奥黛特和芭芭拉
Odette and Barbra
并没有血缘关系
were not biologically related.
我们也找不到芭芭拉在世的家人
And Barbra has no living family we could find.
如果她们不是姐妹
If they're not related,
怎么可能长得这么像
how can Barbra look so much like Odette?
我也不知道
I don't know.
不过我们查到了她之前工作的地方
But we do have an address for her former place of employment,
是个市中心的脱衣舞俱乐部
a strip club in midtown.
我们之前办案的思路是
See, we've been operating under the theory
奥黛特因为她自己惹的事被害
that Odette was murdered because she was Odette.
但如果她是因为她的真实身份而遇害呢
But what if she was murdered because she was really Barbra?
查明芭芭拉的底细
Find out everything you can about Barbra.
与此同时
In the meantime,
我要再询问一遍奥黛特的哥哥保罗
I'm gonna reinterview Odette's brother Paul.
他现在成了嫌犯吗
Is he a person of interest now?
我只是不能相信芭芭拉
I'm just having trouble believing that Barbra managed
能瞒住奥黛特的哥哥一年多
to fool Odette's own brother for over a year.
他得让我相信他不知情
He's gonna have to convince me that he didn't know.
听起来这工作更适合
Well, that sounds like something better done
一对一死磕
one-on-one, mano a mano.
而我想和他们一起去市中心走一趟
Meantime, I want to take a ride downtown with the boys,
-去脱衣舞俱乐部溜溜  -抱歉了 卡塞尔
- check out that strip club. - Sorry, Castle.
人已经满了
Three's a crowd.
怎么了  为什么不让卡塞尔去
What's up? Why you freezing out our boy like that?
我想做个实验
I want to try an experiment.
和卡塞尔一起去会搞砸的
Having Castle along would mess things up.
给你
Here.
戴上我的婚戒
Wear my wedding ring.
干啥呢  把那东西给我拿走
What? Get that thing away from me, man.
这东西很扫兴
It's a mood killer.
我们在夜总会时你就戴着它吧
Just wear it when we're at the club.
为什么
What for?
我已经和所有已婚男性朋友交流过了
See, I been talking to all my married guy friends,
他们说你的那套理论是胡扯
they say that your theory is way off.
戴着婚戒
Wearing a wedding ring
可以让男人更受女人关注  而不是相反
gets them more attention from women, not less.
-所以呢  -所以你把它戴上
- So? - So wear the ring.
我想看看女人会不会继续跟你调情
I want to see if women still flirt with you
同时无视我
and ignore me.
那你不希望卡塞尔来的原因是
So you didn't want Castle to come because...
所有的女人都会和他调情
All the women would flirt with him.
我想知道是不是只是婚戒的原因
I want to know if it's just the ring
让女人们都敬而远之
that's repelling members of the fairer sex.
和婚戒无关  老兄  是你自身原因
It's not the ring, bro. It's you.
当你结婚了一阵子
See, once you've been married for a little while
你会感到一丝乏味和不满
and you're feeling a little bored and unsatisfied,
婚戒会让你得到女人们的爱慕
The ring will get you love from the ladies.
她们想让你脱离苦海
They'll want to take you away from all that
好让你娶她们  然后再一起享受乏味和不满
so that you can be bored and unsatisfied with them.
那现在为何不是这样
Why not now?
因为现在你沉浸在和妻子
Cause now you're all blissfully happy
以及新婚的幸福中
with your wife and whatnot.
你全身散发着蜜月期的臭味
You have the stink of honeymoon phase all over you.
没有哪个女人想接近的
No woman wants to be around that.
会持续多久呢
How long does it last?
这说不准
Well, it's hard to say.
但根据对你和珍妮的了解
But knowing you and Jenny,
也许是一辈子吧
probably forever.
芭比这人呐
Oh, yeah, Barbie.
她成天梦想成为百老汇的舞蹈演员
All she wanted was to be a dancer on Broadway.
她以前经常把这挂在嘴边吗
She used to talk about it a lot, huh?
可不止呢
More than that.
她去美容了  换了发型
She got a makeover, changed her hair,
两年前又给鼻子做了整形
and then two years ago, she got her nose done
其实她鼻子原本就很好
even though her nose looked fine before.
当时芭芭拉有没有和任何人有过纠纷
Back in the day, did Barbra have trouble with anybody,
比如顾客或者男友
say a customer, maybe a boyfriend?
男友  是有的  杰森
Boyfriend, yeah. Jason.
是他吗
Could this be him?
就是他
That's him.
杰森·巴格维尔
Jason Bagwell.
你知道我们如何能找到杰森吗
Do you know where we can find Jason?
他住在字母城[纽约曼哈顿一街区]
He lived over in Alphabet City.
他总是耍阴谋诡计
He was always running some scam,
从芭芭拉那儿借钱用于新的投资
borrowing money from Barbra for some new business venture
而且从不还钱
and never paying her back.
但是她爱他
But she loved him.
疯狂的爱  懂吗
Crazy love, you know?
我懂的
Oh, yeah. I do.
你帮了不少忙  香檀
Well, you've been very helpful, Shantell.
多谢你能抽出时间
Thank you for your time.
如果你愿意  可以等会儿再来
If you wanted, you could come back later.
我的表演八点开始
My show starts at 8:00.
我可能会...
I could probably--
他老婆喊他回家吃饭呢  香檀
He's gotta get home to the little woman, Shantell,
但我们真心感谢你的时间和合作
but we do thank you for your time and your cooperation.
好的
All right.
你发什么神经  老兄
What's wrong with you, man?
你为什么要坏了我的好事
Why you gotta throw salt in my game like that?
你现在不能勾搭女人
You can't pick up on honeys
你会玷污手上戴的婚戒
while wearing the eternal symbol
它可是象征着我对珍妮永恒的爱与承诺
of my love and commitment to Jenny.
-我是不是大声说出来了  -是的
- Did I just say that out loud? - Mm-hmm.
怪不得女人们不和我调情
No wonder women won't flirt with me.
因为她们清楚自己不可能勾引到
I'm a lost cause,
一个深爱着自己妻子的男人
a man in love with his wife.
知足吧  老兄
Enjoy it, my friend.
很多男人都羡慕你呢
A lot of men would switch places with you.
当然我除外  别的男人
Not me. Mnh-mnh. Other men.
那些寂寞单身男
Guys. Unhappy single guys.
是啊  把婚戒还我
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Just give me my ring back,
然后你可以去问香檀的手机号
and you can go get Shantell's phone number.
下一个轮到你了
...You're next up.
搞毛
What the... ow.
怎么了
What?
卡住了
It's stuck.
伙计们正在找芭芭拉的前男友
The guys are out picking up Barbra's ex-boyfriend.
我正好利用这段时间来跟进
I thought I'd use the time to follow up
他们在夜总会得到的情报
on what they learned at the club.
首先芭芭拉·兰戴尔
Starting with the fact that Barbra Landau
确实做了整容手术
did get plastic surgery.
这是她在车管局登记的旧照片
Here is her old D.M.V. Photo.
-她很漂亮  -是的
- She's a pretty girl. - Exactly.
整容没有让她变得更漂亮
Plastic surgery didn't make her look more beautiful.
只是让她变得更像奥黛特·莫顿
It just made her look more like Odette Morton.
还记得她的会计塞缪尔·林奇伯格告诉你的话吗
You remember her accountant Samuel Lynchberg told you
奥黛特为她朋友的鼻部整形买单
that Odette paid for her friend's nose job?
你难道认为芭芭拉就是那个朋友
And you think Barbra is that friend?
你认为她们互相认识
You think they knew each other?
我确定
I know it.
林奇伯格的助手证实了这点
Lynchberg's assistant confirmed it.
奥黛特为芭芭拉的整容和开销买单
Odette paid for Barbra's surgery plus expenses.
我猜你一定对其中的原因有套理论
And I'm guessing you have a theory as to why.
你是清楚奥黛特喜欢派对的
You know Odette loved to party.
从我个人经历来看
Speaking from personal experience,
那种持续的狂欢作乐
I can tell you that all that constant carousing
是不会没有恶果的
does not come without consequences,
比如拘捕  罚义务社区服务之类的
Like arrests, community service hours,
或在某个陌生旅馆房间醒来
waking up in a strange hotel room
头上还套着女孩的内裤  那...
with some girl's panties on your head. That's...
当我没说过
Forget that part.
这就是奥黛特在社区服务时拍的照片
Here is Odette doing her community service hours
是惩罚她在2010年第二次酒后驾车
for her second D.U.I. in 2010.
这是奥黛特和朋友参加一个新娘婚前派对的照片
Here's Odette at a bridal shower with friends.
那又如何
So?
根据时间标识
So according to the time stamps,
这两张照片是同一天拍下的
these photos were taken on the same day
相隔20分钟不到
within 20 minutes of each other.
就是说在救济厨房的其实是芭芭拉
So it was really Barbra at the soup kitchen.
奥黛特犯了罪
Odette would do the crime,
却不想去做社区义务劳动
but she didn't want to do the time.
所以她让假冒的自己去帮她做苦活
So she created a faux-dette to do her dirty work for her.
估计给了不少报酬
A job that I bet paid very well.
也许在城镇的某个疯狂的夜晚
Maybe a wild night on the town
奥黛特来到了脱衣舞夜总会
Brings Odette to the strip club,
在那儿她见到了芭芭拉
where she sees Barbra--
见到了芭芭拉的"一切"
all of Barbra--
而她意识到
and she realizes,
只要花点心思
with a little work,
芭芭拉能成为她完美的分身
Barbra could be the perfect double for her,
去做那些
doing all the unpleasant jobs
奥黛特懒的去做的差事
that Odette simply couldn't be bothered to do--
社区服务  药检
community service hours, drug tests--
再稍加训练和一点整容手术
And with a little training and some surgical tweaks,
芭芭拉还能做更多
Barbra could do even more,
比如和奥黛特的经理人开会
like meetings with Odette's business manager
或是玛格丽特姨妈的无聊午宴
or boring luncheons with her aunt Margaret.
奥黛特的小圈子里没有人知道这诡计
Nobody in Odette's inner circle could've known about the ruse,
所以当火车失事时
so that when the train crashed,
芭芭拉看到了从配角成为主角的机会
Barbra saw her chance to go from understudy to leading lady,
-她抓住了这机会  -这能解释她的转变
- and she took it. - Okay, so that explains the transition,
但我们还是不知道谁杀了她
but we still don't know who killed her.
也许我们知道
Maybe we do.
肯定是某个看到电视后
It would have to be someone that knew
发现其实奥黛特就是芭芭拉的人
Odette was actually Barbra when he saw her on tv,
某个想要从
someone who was looking
她的新生活中捞好处的人
to cash in on her new life...
就像芭芭拉的男朋友杰森
Someone like Barbra's boyfriend Jason.
我是说真的  这太疯狂了  我没有杀人
I'm telling you, this is crazy. I didn't kill anybody.
我认为事情的经过是这样的
Here's what I think happened--
你意识到芭芭拉没有
you realized that Barbra didn't die
在火车意外中死去
in that train accident.
她还活着
She was alive.
而且变成了奥黛特·莫顿  这意味着她很富有
And living as Odette Morton, which meant she was very rich.
你知道她的秘密  而你也想变富
You knew her secret, and you wanted to be rich, too.
但是芭芭拉不是那种
But Barbra wasn't the kind of girl
好不容易攀上枝头
to claw her way into the good life
然后被你这种人占便宜的女孩
and then be taken advantage of by the likes of you.
她拒绝了你  所以你开枪杀了她
She rejected you, and so you shot her.
看到没  这就是我什么都没说的原因
See, this--this is why I didn't come forward.
我知道你们会怀疑我
I knew you'd suspect me.
我们怀疑有动机的人  杰森
We suspect people with motive, Jason.
你们搞错了
You've got it wrong.
是芭芭拉来找的我
Barbra came to me.
两个礼拜前  她出现在我门前
Two weeks ago, she showed up on my doorstep
把整个故事告诉了我
and told me the whole story.
芭芭拉拥有所有她想要的一切
Barbra had everything she could want--
一个完美的生活
a perfect life.
她为什么会冒险联系你呢
Why would she risk it all by getting in touch with you?
因为她想我了
Because she missed me.
而且奥黛特的生活并不像芭芭拉
And Odette's life wasn't as perfect
想的那么完美
as Barbra thought.
芭芭拉很孤独
Barbra was lonely,
她想跟我重归于好
and she wanted to get back together.
她告诉我她发现了一些关于奥黛特的事情
She told me she had found out some stuff about Odette,
她过去的什么秘密
um, secrets from her past.
-什么秘密  -我不知道
- What kind of secrets? - I don't know.
但是她说  如果有人发现了
But she said, if anyone found out,
一切都会被毁了
it would all be over for her.
你觉得她是因为这个秘密被杀的吗
You think this secret got her killed?
她说她可以利用这个秘密
She said she could use it to her advantage.
她只是还需要一些信息
She just needed more information.
能够作为筹码
Information was-- was leverage,
那信息可以保护她
it would protect her,
但是她必须要快点行动
but she had to move fast.
但她还是不够快
And she didn't move fast enough.
芭芭拉从小一直跳舞跳到大
Barbra had been dancing since she was a little kid,
她的梦想就是成为百老汇的明星
and all she ever wanted was to be a star on Broadway.
她就要成功了
And she was so close.
所以不是她自己的过去
So it wasn't something from her own past
使得芭芭拉被杀的
that got Barbra killed.
而是奥黛特的
It was something from Odette's.
在她被害一周前
Okay, so a week before her death,
芭芭拉假扮的奥黛特  举止古怪
Barbra, as Odette, is acting odd,
她错过彩排
she's missing rehearsals--
她找到前男友
She seeks out her ex,
告诉他奥黛特的完美生活并不完美
tells him that Odette's perfect life isn't so perfect
而且奥黛特过去的某件事情
and that there's something in Odette's past
-是个麻烦  -是的
- that's a problem. - Right.
她需要信息  她去哪了呢
So she needs information. So where does she go?
苏珊·斯坦纳
Suzanne Steiner.
还记得吗  被害那天芭芭拉和她一起喝咖啡
Remember, Barbra met her for coffee the day she died?
她想和苏珊聊聊旧时光
She wanted to talk to Suzanne about old times.
我不知道我能帮什么忙
I'm not sure what help I can be.
那天奥黛特看上去挺正常的
Odette seemed fine the day that I saw her.
是吗
Mm-hmm.
我一直忘记她不是奥黛特
Oh, I keep forgetting that she wasn't Odette.
她们实在是太像了
Oh, the resemblance was remarkable.
你说她想要叙旧
You said that she wanted to reminisce.
你们两个有多亲近
How close were the two of you?
我父亲在她祖父家做了
Well, my dad was the butler in her grandfather's home
二十年的管家  所以
for 20 years, so...
我们两个可以说是一起长大的
we practically grew up together.
那她想要谈些什么
And what did she want to talk about?
她问起了她祖父
Well, she asked about her grandfather.
奥黛特的祖父
Well, Odette's grandfather.
她说起他们以前有多亲近
She talked about how close they had been.
然后还问起他去世的那天
And then she asked about the day that he died.
-他是在睡梦中过世的  是不是  -是的
- He died in his sleep, didn't he? - Yeah.
是的  他那时已经98岁了
Yeah, he was 98.
很奇怪她会问我
It was odd that she asked,
因为那时候我不在那里
because I wasn't there,
但她在的
But she was--
奥黛特在  还有我父亲
Odette was-- along with my father,
在我提醒了她之后
and when I reminded her of that,
她问起了我父亲
she asked about my dad.
她说她想和他  叙叙旧
She said she wanted to... catch up with him.
你知道他们两个联系过了吗
Do you know if the two of them ever spoke?
我把他的号码给了她
Well, I gave her his number,
但我不知道发生了什么
but I-I'm not sure what happened.
不行  还是拿不下来
Mnh-mnh. It's not coming off.
像是焊在我手上了一样
It's like it soldered itself onto my hand.
说不定是被邪灵附体了
Maybe it's possessed, you know,
就像是斯蒂芬·金小说里被诅咒的邪器
like some kind of cursed object from a Stephen King story.
我该怎么跟我老婆说  我没戴结婚戒指
How can I tell my wife that I'm not wearing my wedding ring
是因为我把戒指借给埃斯波西托
because I lent it to Esposito as an experiment
来看脱衣舞女会不会和我调情
to see if strippers would flirt with me?
也许她会觉得挺好笑的
Maybe she'll see the humor in it.
-绝对不可能  -你死定了
- Not a chance. - You're a dead man.
好了  查尔斯·卡森
So Charles Carson,
奥黛特死去祖父的前管家
former butler to Odette's late grandfather.
没有犯罪记录  但是听好了
No record, but get this--
他的名字有点耳熟  我就查了
his name rang a bell, so I looked up
星期三节目录制的宾客名单
the guest list from Wednesday's taping,
他在上面
and he's on it.
奥黛特在最后时刻加了一张卡森先生的票
Odette called in a last-minute ticket request for Mr Carson.
这么说他在节目现场
So he was at the show.
是的  保安说他是在2点15进场的
Yes, security has him going through at 2:15,
但在那之后就没有人记得见过他了
but after that, no one remembers seeing him.
苏珊说冒牌货
Okay, so Suzanne said that faux-dette
想谈论她祖父去世的那天
wanted to talk about the day her grandfather died.
如果这就是芭芭拉发现的秘密呢
What if this was the secret that Barbra was on to?
如果格兰姆·莫顿不是自然死亡
What if Graham Morton didn't die of natural causes
而她认为这个查尔斯·卡森
and she felt somehow Charles Carson here
与此事有关呢
had something to do with it?
我们得去看看格兰姆·莫顿的验尸报告
We need to see Graham Morton's autopsy report.
根据我对验尸报告的研究
Based on my reading of the coroner's report,
我能看出为什么格兰姆·莫顿会被判为自然死亡
I can see why Graham Morton's death was ruled natural causes.
然而
However --
转折来了
Ooh. There's a however.
非常大的转折  说吧
A very big however. Tell 'em.
有些异常之处让我觉得可疑
There were some anomalies I found suspicious.
莫顿先生的双眼都出现了淤点
Evidence of petechiae in both eyes,
他的鼻梁右侧还有近期造成的淤青
fresh bruising on the right side of Mr. Morton's nose,
而这一切可能是  比如说
which could have happened if, say,
有人用枕头捂住他的脸造成的
someone was holding a pillow over his face.
总之言之  有充分的证据表明
All in all, I think there's ample evidence
莫顿先生是被谋杀的
that Mr. Morton was murdered.
充分的证据
Ample.
是谋杀
Murdered.
我太为你骄傲了
I am just so proud.
-老爸  注意公私分明  -好吧
- Dad, work. Boundaries.  - Right.
还有件事  我要求对方把档案发来时
One more thing. When I requested the file be sent over,
职员告诉我
the clerk told me
我是本周第二个要求看这个的人
that I was the second person this week to ask for it.
奥黛特·莫顿周二也去过那里
Odette Morton was there on Tuesday.
这么说芭芭拉发现奥黛特的祖父是被谋杀的
So Barbra realized Odette's grandfather was murdered
她肯定也想到管家卡森
and must have thought Carson the butler
跟这件事脱不了干系
had something to do with it.
而当卡森发现
And then when Carson figured out
芭芭拉知道得太多了
that Barbra knew too much,
就把她给杀了
he killed her.
咱们明天一早就得把他叫来问话
We're gonna bring him in first thing in the morning.
还要以双重谋杀罪逮捕他
And arrest him for a double murder.
早上好
Good morning.
我可一点都不好
Speak for yourself.
理查德  我这次真是搞砸了
Oh, Richard. I really messed up.
我就是为了逞一时只气
I just let my ego get the better of me,
这下乌娜·马可尼绝不会赞扬我的学校了
now Oona Marconi is never gonna endorse my school.
她也行还会为泄恨写些负面报道
She'll probably write something negative just out of spite.
你还是有机会扭转乾坤的
Well, there is a chance you can still turn this around.
但问题是你愿意向一个
But are you willing to apologize to someone
如此过分的人道歉吗
who doesn't really deserve it?
亲爱的  我觉得这现在根本就不是
Darling, I don't think a simple apology
道个歉就能解决的问题了
is gonna get me out of this.
那我就只好引用唐·维托·柯里昂的一句名言了
Then in the wise words of Don Vito Corleone...
你得给她提出一个
you need to make her an offer
她无法拒绝的提议
she can't refuse.
如果我能
And if there's anything --
如果我能帮上忙的话
if there's anything I can do to help,
-告诉我一声  -我会的
- you let me know.  - I will.
我会的
I will.
卡森先生  你为格兰姆·莫顿工作了二十五余年
Mr. Carson, you worked for Graham Morton for over 25 years.
据我了解  你跟他的孙子和孙女关系很好
I understand that you were very close with his grandkids.
我们关系的确很亲近
Well, as -- as close as one could be
但我们仍是
while still maintaining
雇主与雇员的关系
the employer-servant relationship.
所以当死者打电话邀请你
So when the victim called you and invited you
去参加周三晚上的《热舞之夜》的录制
to the "Night of Dance" taping on Wednesday,
-你欣然同意了  -我乐意至极
- you said yes.  - I was delighted.
她让我在录制结束后跟她聚聚
She asked me to meet her afterwards
她说她有个问题要问我
and said that she had a question for me,
但正如你们所知的  录制取消了
but of course, as you know, they canceled the show,
而我直到第二天才知道究竟发生了什么
and I didn't find out until the next day what had happened.
我完全不知道
I had no idea
那个女孩根本就不是奥黛特
that that girl wasn't Odette
我也不知道她要找我谈些什么
and no idea why she wanted to talk to me.
她想找你谈格兰姆·莫顿去世那天的事
She wanted to talk to you about the day that Graham Morton died.
她为什么会对这个感兴趣
Why would she care about that?
她似乎找到了一些证据表明
It seems she had some evidence
莫顿先生不是自然死亡的
that Mr. Morton didn't die of natural causes.
你把我搞糊涂了  你是说他是被谋杀的吗
I don't understand. Are you saying that he was murdered?
莫顿先生去世当天你也在他家  对吧
You were at the house that day, weren't you?
上帝啊  你不会认为我
Oh, good lord. You don't think that I had --
你是和他关系最近的人
You were the person closest to him.
你有充足的机会
You had ample opportunity.
我们看过遗嘱了
We've seen the will.
他给你留下了很大一笔遗产
He left you a generous bequest.
我是绝对不会伤害莫顿先生的
I would never have hurt Mr. Morton.
但是那个女人
But that woman --
那个假扮成奥黛特的女人
the woman who pretended to be Odette --
她可能猜中了他的死因
she might be right about his death.
其实  有可能
In fact, it's possible
她真认为我对此知情
that she believed that I knew something.
告诉我
Tell me,
莫顿先生是怎么死的
how did Mr. Morton die?
他是被人闷死的吗
Was he smothered?
你为什么这么问
Why would you ask that?
他去世的那个月  家里的气氛一直很紧张
The month he died, there was tension in the household.
莫顿先生不喜欢
Odette was seeing someone
奥黛特当时的男朋友
of whom Mr. Morton did not approve.
你知道是谁吗
Do you know who?
不知道  但是他命令她跟那个人分手
No, but he ordered her to break it off,
当然了  那天奥黛特哭得稀里哗啦
and of course, that day Odette was crying,
几乎整个早上都躲在房间里哭
she spent most of the morning in her room.
一点左右时  莫顿先生说他想睡一会儿
At about 1:00, Mr. Morton said that he wanted to take a nap,
于是我把床上的枕头都拿走了
so I cleared the bed of all the pillows.
他喜欢平躺着睡
He preferred a-a flat surface.
过了一会儿以后
Now a few moments later,
楼下厨房出了点乱子
there was a commotion down in the kitchen.
奥黛特把三明治放在烤箱里烤太久了
Odette had put a sandwich in the toaster oven too long,
结果发生了小火灾
and it had caused a small fire.
我们把火扑灭了
We put it out,
然后我去楼上查看莫顿先生
and then I went back upstairs to check on Mr. Morton,
他已经死了
and he was dead.
那时我就注意到了
And that's when I noticed it.
注意到了什么
Noticed what?
床上有个枕头
A pillow on the bed.
而我很确定我之前把所有的枕头都拿走了
And I was sure that I had taken them all off.
所以我跟奥黛特说了
So I told Odette about it,
但是她说肯定是我记错了
but she said my mind was playing tricks on me,
我就没再追究
so I let it go.
卡森先生  你在厨房的时候
Mr. Carson, when you were in the kitchen,
奥黛特是否曾离开过你的视线
was there ever a moment that Odette was out of your sight?
没有
No.
我知道她是无辜的
I-I knew she was innocent.
她不是无辜的
She wasn't innocent.
她是为了引开你
She was the distraction.
奥黛特把你引到厨房
Odette got you down to the kitchen
而她的同伙则借机谋杀了她的祖父
while her accomplice went and murdered her grandfather.
而当芭芭拉·兰戴尔搞清了事实真相后
And then when Barbra Landau figured out the truth,
那个同伙把她也杀掉了
the accomplice murdered her, too.
感谢你能来  林奇伯格先生
Thank you for coming in, Mr. Lynchberg.
林奇伯格先生
Mr. Lynchberg,
作为莫顿家族的财务顾问
being the Morton family financial advisor,
你肯定对他们一家人的
that must give you pretty good insight
私生活了如指掌吧
into their -- their personal lives, right?
知道一个人都把钱花在什么地方
Well, looking at what people spend their money on,
的确会让你对这个人有所了解
you get to know folks pretty well.
那你有多了解奥黛特呢
And how well did you know Odette?
就跟我对其他客户的了解一样
As well as any of my clients.
但毕竟我之前多次为她的生活方式说她
But given the lectures that I gave her about her lifestyle,
或许更了解她吧
maybe more so.
据我们所知  在奥黛特的祖父去世的那段时间
We understand, about the time her grandfather died,
她正在跟某个人交往
Odette was dating someone,
但她祖父不同意他们在一起
someone her grandfather didn't approve of.
这并不奇怪
Mm. Well, that's not surprising.
他们经常意见相左
The two of them rarely saw eye to eye.
你记得奥黛特的男朋友是谁吗
This boyfriend -- do you remember who he was?
不记得  为什么问这个
No. Why?
因为我们认为他伙同
Well, because we think that he conspired
奥黛特杀死了她的祖父
with Odette to kill her grandfather
而他后来又杀死了芭芭拉
and then he killed Barbra
因为她马上就要搞清楚事情的真相了
when she was on the verge of figuring it all out.
你确定你不记得了吗
You're sure you don't remember?
确定
Mnh-mnh.
我们跟奥黛特的哥哥通过电话
Well, we just spoke with Odette's brother,
他记得
and he remembers.
事实上  他记得她的男友是你
In fact, he remembers it being you.
他说你们两个想要结婚
He said that the two of you wanted to get married,
但是奥黛特的祖父威胁说要剥夺她的继承权
but Odette's grandfather threatened to cut her off.
奥黛特这样的女孩
Now a girl like Odette,
靠着你那可怜的六位数工资
she could never be happy living off
她可不会快活
a meager 6-figure salary like yours.
她得继承遗产
She needed to inherit.
但那老头子一直不死
But that old man refused to die.
于是她就说服你
So she convinced you
利用她在厨房搞出的乱子
to go upstairs and smother him to death with a pillow
上楼用枕头将他闷死
while she created a distraction in the kitchen.
问题解决了
Problem solved.
只不过她一拿到钱
Except once she had her money,
她离开了你  继续她派对动物的生活
she left you, went back to her partying lifestyle.
她利用了你  但是你却束手无策
She used you, but there wasn't anything you could do about it.
至少在否认谋杀的前提下没有法子
At least not without admitting to the murder.
你们无法证明
You can't prove that.
他的死被判定是自然死亡
His death wasn't even ruled a homicide.
是的  但芭芭拉·兰戴尔是被谋杀的
No, but Barbra Landau's was.
警员在你办公室后的垃圾桶里
Uniforms found this 9 millimeter
找到了这把9毫米口径手枪
in the dumpster behind your offices.
弹道检测相匹配
Ballistics match.
杀死芭芭拉·兰戴尔的就是这把枪
This is the same gun that was used to kill Barbra Landau.
而且上面
And it's got...
全是你的指纹
your fingerprints all over it.
上个月  她的信用卡账单多得吓人
Last month, when her credit card bills were so high,
我以为她又开始吸毒了
I thought she was slipping back into her old ways.
我对她说
I said to her,
我们做了那些事  得到这笔钱
"We didn't risk everything to get this money
不是为了让你毁掉自己
so you could let it ruin your life."
她看着我
And she looked at me, and...
我看得出
I could tell,
她根本就不知道我在说什么
she had no idea what I was talking about.
就在那时
In that moment,
我知道她不是我的奥黛特
I knew that she wasn't my Odette.
也是在那时她知道了你的秘密
And that's how she got on to you.
这个芭芭拉跟我说如果我替她保密
So this Barbra told me that if I kept her secret,
她也会守口如瓶
she would keep mine.
她以为这样我们就扯平了
She thought we were even.
她以为她可以就这样变身为奥黛特
She thought that she could just take the place of Odette.
要我怎么做
I mean, wh-what-- what was I supposed to do,
让这个脱衣舞女住在她家
just let some dirty stripper live in her house
穿她的衣服  勒索我吗
and wear her clothes and--and blackmail me?
她不配过奥黛特的生活
Odette deserved better.
怎么了
What's going on?
我就是在想
I was just thinking
我们靠着梦想维持自己的生活
how we rely on dreams to keep us going in life
而当梦想
and how sad it is
毁掉我们的生活时  这有多可悲
when they become the things that tear us down.
芭芭拉·兰戴尔的经历那是特例
Yeah, well, that might be the case for Barbra Landau,
但并不是每个梦想没实现的人都这样啊
but not for everyone with dreams that didn't come true.
拿蕾妮来说吧
I mean, take Lanie for instance.
她想成为一个舞者  结果成了医生
She wanted to be a dancer. She became a doctor.
一点都不可悲啊
That's not so bad, is it?
你呢
Hmm. What about you?
我知道你是因为
I mean, I know you became a cop
你母亲被谋杀才当警察的
because your mother was murdered,
但之前你肯定有别的梦想
but there had to be something before that.
小时候的凯特·贝克特长大想做什么
What did little Kate Beckett want to be when she grew up?
在斯坦福大学时  我念法律预科
At Stanford, I was pre-law.
那么说你的梦想是在最高法院打官司
So your dream was to argue a case before the supreme court.
是的  我当时正在努力
Mm-hmm. Yep, I was on my way
成为第一位女性首席法官
to becoming the first female chief justice.
不赖
Not bad.
拿不下来  你知道吗
Ah, it won't-- yeah, you know what?
我跟脱衣舞女约会要迟到了
I'm late for my stripper date, man.
不行  不行
Whoa. No, no, no. No, no, no, no.
我今晚不能不戴戒指回家啊
I cannot go home again without ring on my finger tonight.
我家沙发有个弹簧坏了  我的背...
Our couch has a loose spring. My back--
你试肥皂了吗
Did you try soap?
-试了  -那是我们在先试的
- Yeah. - Yeah, that was, like, the first thing we did.
-烹饪油呢  -我没想过用烹饪油
- Cooking spray? - I didn't think about cooking spray.
上哪找烹饪油去
Where am I gonna find cooking spray?
用这个
Here.
像丝绸一样
It's like silk.
可能会起作用
That might work.
我觉得能拿下来了
Oh, yeah. I think it's coming. Yeah?
至少从我手指上拿下来了
At least it's off my finger.
乌娜  你能来真是太感谢了
Oona, thank you so much for stopping by.
谢谢  玛莎
Thank you, Martha.
我一定会专栏上找些地方
And I'll be sure to find a few inches of column space
提及你的学校的
to mention your little school.
太好了  谢谢你  你能帮忙真是太好了
Oh, good. Thank you. I really appreciate that, dear.
理查德  很好
Oh, Richard, good.
你刚好来得及跟乌娜道别
You're just in time to say good-bye to Oona.
很高兴再次见到你
Oh. How nice to see you again.
我也很高兴见到你
It's lovely to see you as well.
我期待接到你的电话
And I, uh, look forward to hearing from you.
我的电话
Hearing from--
我知道你很忙  亲爱的
Well, I know you're in a hurry, dear, and, uh,
我再打给你  我们一起吃午饭
I'll call you. We will have lunch.
好的  拜
Yes. Bye-bye.
很圆满
All's well that ends well.
妈  为什么乌娜·马可尼会期待
Mother, why would Oona Marconi be looking forward
我的电话
to hearing from me?
是你说的如果需要你的帮忙
Well, you did say, if there was any way that you could help--
你应该先跟我打招呼
That you should let me know.
你先斩后奏到底答应她什么了
Exactly what did you promise her without asking me first?
你会读读她的小说
That you would read her novel...
妈
Oh, mother.
评价一下  然后交给你的出版商
And critique it and give it to your publisher.
小说讲得是
It is the inspiring story
一位年轻的女士从百货商店店员
of a young woman's journey from department store clerk
变成百老汇明星的感人故事
to world-renowned broadway star.
小妞文学啊  老妈这真不是我的...
Chick lit? Mother this is really not my--
亲爱的
Oh, and, darling,
在你评价她的小说时  措辞友善一点
When you give her your thoughts, do be kind,
成为小说家是她的梦想
because it's always been her dream to be a novelist.
友善
Be kind.
为了你  老妈
For you, mother,
我可以友善
I can be kind.